Sylvia Beach Papers, 1887-1966 (bulk 1920s-1950s ): Finding Aid
Princeton University Library. Department of Rare Books and Special Collections.
- Series 2: Shakespeare & Company, 1912-1962; more than 43 boxes (3 partial)
  - Manuscripts and Publications, 1914-1962; 12 boxes (2 partial)
    - Ulysses, 1914-1948; 9 boxes (1 partial)
      - Ulysses Proofs, 1921 September 28-1927; 4 boxes (2 partial)
        - Ulysses Proofs, 1921 December 8-1922 January 5; 1 folder (Folder 3)
          Placards 1-5, 5 bis, 6-13. Includes several different proofs for most signatures, and a number of duplicates. Printer's dates range from 8 Dec. 1921 to 5 Jan. 1922.
        - Ulysses Proofs, 1926 March 21-April 26; 1 folder (Folder 1)
          Preliminary page proofs for the 8th printing of Ulysses (May 1926), in which the type was entirely reset and the text, consequently, expanded to 735 pages. In this reset printing most of the "Additional Corrections" of the 4th-7th printings were incorporated into the text.
          Sig. 2, pp. 17-32 Sig. 7, pp. 97-112 Sig. 10-11, pp. 145-176 Sig. 14, pp. 209-224 Sig. 16-17, pp. 241-272 Sig. 21, pp. 321-336 Sig. 24-46, pp. 369-735
          Printer's dates range from 21 March 1926 (Sig. 14) to 26 April 1926 (Sig. 45).
          The corrections on this proof (presumably made by Sylvia Beach) are typographical corrections. There appear to be no substantive additions or changes.
        - Ulysses Proofs, 1927 May; 1 folder (Folder 2)
          Page proof for the 9th printing of Ulysses. The 9th printing used the reset plates of the 8th printing, but these proofs would seem to indicate that there were a few new corrections for the 9th (something not indicated in the standard bibliographies). Proofs initialed by Sylvia Beach.
          Sig. 2, pp. 17-32 Sig. 10-11, pp. 145-176 Sig. 14-17, pp. 209-272 Sig. 21, pp. 321-336 Sig. 24-46, pp. 369-735
        - Ulysses Book Jacket Proofs, undated; 1 folder (Folder 3)
        - Ulysses Errata Sheets, undated; 1 folder (Folder 1)
        - Unauthorized Disposal of Ulysses Proofs, 1927; 1 folder (Folder 2)
      - Orders and Subscriptions, 1920-1933; 2 boxes (1 partial)
        - List of Clients Interested in Ulysses, undated; 1 folder (Folder 3)
        - Ulysses Subscribers, undated; 1 folder (Folder 4)
        - Blank Subscription Forms, undated; 1 folder (Folder 5)
        - Slips with Names of Subscribers, 1922-1923; 1 folder (Folder 6)
        - Order Forms-A, 1921-1922; 1 folder (Folder 7)
        - Order Forms-B, 1921-1922; 1 folder (Folder 8)
        - Order Forms-C, 1921-1928; 1 folder (Folder 9)
        - Order Forms-D, 1920-1922; 1 folder (Folder 10)
        - Order Forms-E, 1921-1924; 1 folder (Folder 11)
        - Order Forms-F, 1921-1933; 1 folder (Folder 12)
        - Order Forms-G, 1921-1927; 1 folder (Folder 13)
        - Order Forms-H, 1922-1927; 1 folder (Folder 14)
        - Order Forms-I, 1921-1927; 1 folder (Folder 15)
        - Order Forms-J, 1921-1922; 1 folder (Folder 1)
        - Order Forms-K, 1922; 1 folder (Folder 2)
        - Order Forms-L, 1921-1927; 1 folder (Folder 3)
        - Order Forms-M, 1922-1927; 1 folder (Folder 4)
        - Order Forms-N, 1921-1922; 1 folder (Folder 5)
        - Order Forms-O, 1922; 1 folder (Folder 6)
        - Order Forms-P, 1921-1927; 1 folder (Folder 7)
        - Order Forms-Q, 1921-1922; 1 folder (Folder 8)
        - Order Forms-R, 1921-1927; 1 folder (Folder 9)
        - Order Forms-S, 1921-1924; 1 folder (Folder 10)
        - Order Forms-T, 1921-1922; 1 folder (Folder 11)
        - Order Forms-U, V, 1922; 1 folder (Folder 12)
        - Order Forms-W, 1921-1922; 1 folder (Folder 13)
        - Order Forms-Z, undated; 1 folder (Folder 14)
        - Ulysses Orders Received: Envelopes, 1922; 1 folder (Folder 15)
      - Correspondence Regarding the Publication of Ulysses, 1921-1937 June 8; 7 folders
        - General Correspondence Concerning Ulysses, 1921 June 18; 1 folder (Folder 1)
        - General Correspondence Concerning Ulysses, 1922 February 9-1937 June 8; 1 folder (Folder 2)
        - General Correspondence Regarding Images, 1927-1931; 1 folder (Folder 3)
        - Barnet Braverman Regarding Smuggling of Ulysses, 1922 April 15-1924 July 17; 1 folder (Folder 4)
        - Maurice Darantiere, Dijon, Concerning Printing of Ulysses, 1921-1934; 1 folder (Folder 5)
        - George Bernard Shaw Regarding Ulysses, 1921 June 11; 1 folder Copy. (Folder 6)
        - Harriet Weaver to The Egoist Press Regarding Publication of Ulysses, 1921 May 9; 1 folder (Folder 7)
      - Ulysses Advertising and Reviews, 1923-1929; 4 folders
        - First Edition Prospectus, undated; 1 folder (Folder 8)
        - Printed Announcements, undated; 1 folder (Folder 9)
          Contains announcements for first, fourth, seventh, and eighth editions.
        - Advertisements for the 8th Printing, undated; 1 folder (Folder 10)
        - Press Reviews, 1923-1929; 1 folder (Folder 11)
      - Ulysses Copyright Issues, 1914-1933; 3 boxes (1 partial)
        - List of Editions Published by Shakespeare & Company and Pirated Editions, undated; 1 folder (Folder 12)
        - Press Notices Regarding Pirating, 1926-1927; 1 folder (Folder 13)
        - General Correspondence on Pirating of Ulysses, 1922-1931; 1 folder (Folder 14)
        - General Correspondence on Pirating of Ulysses, 1925-1933; 1 folder (Folder 15)
        - Pirating Protest, Lists of Addresses of Signers, 1927; 1 folder (Folder 1)
        - Pirating Protest Forms, 1927; 1 folder (Folder 2)
        - Pirating Protest Forms, 1927-1929; 1 folder (Folder 3)
        - Pirating Protest, Marked Lists, 1927-1930; 1 folder (Folder 4)
        - Pirating Protest, Plates of Signatures, undated; 1 folder (Folder 1)
          Includes the signatures of Sherwood Anderson, E. M. Forster, Ernest Hemingway, Virginia Woolf as well as others.
        - James Joyce to Signers of Pirating Protest, 1927; 1 folder (Folder 2)
        - Ulysses Pirating: Herbert Devine, The Humanist, 1927; 1 folder (Folder 3)
        - Pirating, Two Worlds Monthly and The Humanist, 1927; 1 folder (Folder 4)
        - Pirating, Copyright Information, 1914-1933; 1 folder (Folder 5)
      - Serial Publication, 1919 July-1921; 2 folders
        - The Egoist, 1919 July; 1 folder (Folder 1)
        - The Little Review, 1921 September-December; 1 folder (Folder 2)
      - Accounts and Royalties, 1922-1931; 1 folder (Folder 3-6)
        Includes account statements, notebooks of expenditures and royalties, check stubs, and general notes.
      - Foreign Language Editions, 1925-1948; 6 folders
        - American Edition, Publishers, 1931-1932; 1 folder (Folder 7)
        - French Edition, Printed Announcements, 1925; 1 folder (Folder 8)
        - German Edition, Rhein-Verlag, 1928-1948; 1 folder (Folder 9)
        - German Edition, Printed Announcements, undated; 1 folder (Folder 10)
        - German Translation, 1926; 1 folder (Folder 11)
        - Czech Translation, 1927-1928; 1 folder (Folder 12)
      - Ulysses First Edition Book Jacket, undated; 1 folder (Folder 13)
    - Exiles, 1922-1956; 11 folders
      Contains material documenting Sylvia Beach's role in having the play produced in France as well as correspondence regarding foreign translations.
      - Power of Attorney for Sylvia Beach, 1922 August 13; 1 folder (Folder 1)
      - Signed Contract with The Neighborhood Playhouse, New York, 1924 June 28; 1 folder (Folder 2)
      - The Neighborhood Playhouse Production Correspondence, 1923-1925; 1 folder (Folder 3)
      - The Neighborhood Playhouse Production Playbill, 1925; 1 folder (Folder 4)
      - The Neighborhood Playhouse Production Photographs, 1925; 1 folder (Folder 5)
      - Jacques Copeau to James Joyce, 1922-1923; 1 folder (Folder 6)
      - Sylvia Beach to Jacques Copeau, undated; 1 folder (Folder 7)
        Draft with James Joyce's suggestions.
      - Publicity, 1956; 1 folder (Folder 8)
      - German Edition and Other Publishing Efforts, 1922-1930; 1 folder (Folder 9)
      - French Translation by Pierre Lionel Méry, undated; 1 folder (Folder 10)
      - Folder Bearing James Joyce's Autograph, undated; 1 folder (Folder 11)
    - Pomes Penyeach, 1927-1938; 3 folders
      - Correspondence, 1927-1938; 1 folder (Folder 12)
      - Diary of Publication, 1927-1931; 1 folder (Folder 13)
      - Announcements and Other Printed Forms, circa 1927; 1 folder (Folder 14)
    - Our Exagmination Round His Factification for Incamination of Work in Progress, 1928-1962; 2 boxes (1 partial)
      - Correspondence, 1928-1961; portions of 2 boxes
        - 1929 Edition: General Correspondence, 1928-1929; 1 folder (Folder 15)
        - 1929 Edition: Publisher Correspondence, 1929-1937; 1 folder (Folder 16)
        - 1962 Edition: Author Correspondence, 1960-1961; 1 folder (Folder 17)
        - 1962 Edition: Publisher Correspondence, 1949-1961; 1 folder (Folder 1)
        - 1962 Edition: Publisher Correspondence (German Publishers), 1960-1961; 1 folder (Folder 2)
        - 1962 Edition: Correspondence Regarding Microfilms, 1959-1960; 1 folder (Folder 3)
      - 1929 Edition: Announcements, 1 folder (Folder 4)
      - 1962 Edition: Reviews, 1 folder (Folder 5)
      - 1962 Edition: Distribution Notebook, 1960-1961; 1 folder (Folder 6)
      - Our Exagmination Round His Factification for Incamination of Work in Progress, 1929; 1 folder (Folder 7)
        2 copies of the 1929 edition.
      - Our Exagmination Round His Factification for Incamination of Work in Progress, 1962; 1 folder (Folder 8)
        2 copies of the 1962 edition.
    - Anaïs Nin on D. H. Lawrence, undated; 1 folder (Folder 1)
    - Campbell, Alan, undated; 1 folder (Folder 2)
    - Heaton, Hedley, undated; 1 folder (Folder 3)
    - Frankenberg, Lloyd, 1938; 1 folder (Folder 4)
    - Monson, Cecil, 1935; 1 folder (Folder 5)
    - Scott Graham Williamson, undated; 1 folder (Folder 6)
    - Thomas, W. G., 1931; 1 folder (Folder 7)
    - Der Junge Herr: Die Erlebnisse Eines Sterblichen, undated; 1 folder (Folder 8)
    - Unidentified Manuscripts, undated; 1 folder (Folder 9)
    - Unidentified Typescripts, undated; 1 folder (Folder 10)
  - Author Readings, 1931-1937; portions of 2 boxes
    - Eliot, T. S., 1936; 1 folder (Folder 11)
    - Sitwell, Edith, 1931 January 7; 1 folder (Folder 12)
    - Correspondence and Related Material, 1931-1937; 1 folder (Folder 1)
    - Correspondence and Related Material, 1935-1937; portion of 1 folder (Folder 2)
    - Publicity, 1937; 1 folder (Folder 3)
    - Publicity, 1936-1937; 1 folder (Folder 4)
    - Record Book, 1936-1937; 1 folder (Folder 5)
    - Bills, 1937; 1 folder (Folder 6)
    - Door Sign, undated; 1 folder (Folder 7)
  - Walt Whitman Exhibit, 1926; 4 boxes (3 partial)
    - Catalogue, 1926; 1 folder (Folder 8)
    - Correspondence, 1926; 1 folder (Folder 9)
    - Invitations, 1926; 1 folder (Folder 10)
    - Guest Book, 1926; 1 folder (Folder 11)
    - Account Book, 1926; 1 folder (Folder 1)
    - Flyers, 1926; 1 folder (Folder 2)
    - Scrapbook, 1926; 1 folder
    - Mounted Signs for Walt Whitman Exposition, undated; 1 folder
    - Newspaper Clippings, 1926; 1 folder (Folder 3)
  - Business Correspondence, 1919-1962; 6 boxes (2 partial)
    Includes inquiries received after the closing of Shakespeare & Company but maintained with the original file run.
    - James Joyce Inquiries, 1922-1962 May 22; portions of 2 boxes
      - Ulysses Bookshop to Sylvia Beach Regarding the Unauthorized Publication of Two Joyce Essays, 1930 January 9-1948 September 7; 1 folder (Folder 4)
      - Inquiries to James Joyce Received at Shakespeare & Company, 1922 -1931; 1 folder (Folder 5)
      - General Inquiries Re: James Joyce, 1924-1960; 1 folder (Folder 6)
      - Monro, Saw & Co., Solicitors for Joyce, 1948 November 1-December 29; 1 folder (Folder 7)
      - Morris, Lloyd to Sylvia Beach Regarding James Joyce, 1924-1925; 1 folder (Folder 8)
      - Sims, George to Sylvia Beach Regarding James Joyce's Works, 1955 May 16-1957 April 9; 1 folder (Folder 9)
      - Slocum, John J. to Sylvia Beach Regarding James Joyce, 1947 February 6-1951 February 10; 1 folder (Folder 10)
      - The Calendar Inquiries Concerning James Joyce, 1925-1927; 1 folder (Folder 11)
      - The Criterion Inquiries Concerning James Joyce, 1925 May-September; 1 folder (Folder 12)
      - The Dial Inquiries Concerning James Joyce, 1926; 1 folder (Folder 13)
        Also included is correspondence with Marianne Moore concerning "The Dial's" refusal to publish a manuscript by James Joyce verbatim.
      - Prométhée Inquiries Concerning James Joyce, 1930 May 5; 1 folder (Folder 14)
      - This Quarter Inquiries Concerning James Joyce, 1925-1930; 1 folder (Folder 15)
      - Transition Inquiries Concerning James Joyce, 1927-1932; 1 folder (Folder 16)
      - Ulysses Recording, 1924 October 20-1962 May 22; portions of 2 boxes
        - BBC, BC, BIRS Correspondence Regarding Joyce Ulysses Recording, 1949-1960; 1 folder (Folder 17)
        - Caedmon Publishers Correspondence Regarding Joyce Ulysses Recording, 1956 April 16-1961 April 7; 1 folder (Folder 1)
        - C. K. Ogden Correspondence Regarding Joyce Ulysses Recording, 1929 April 23-1938 November 24; 1 folder (Folder 2)
        - Inquiries Regarding Joyce Ulysses Recording, 1924 October 20-1950 May 7; 1 folder (Folder 3)
        - Inquiries Regarding Joyce Ulysses Recording, 1929 November 17-1961 May 17; 1 folder (Folder 4)
        - Rein-Verlag (Dr. Brody) Correspondence Regarding Joyce Ulysses Recording, 1957 April 24-1962 May 22; 1 folder (Folder 5)
    - General Inquiries, 1919-1962; portions of 2 boxes
      - Orders and Inquiries, 1925-1940; 1 folder (Folder 6)
      - Orders and Inquiries, 1926-1946; 1 folder (Folder 7)
      - General Inquiries, 1919-1954; 1 folder (Folder 8)
      - General Inquiries, 1920-1958; 1 folder (Folder 9)
      - General Inquiries, 1925-1962; 1 folder (Folder 1)
      - Student Inquiries, 1931-1961; 1 folder (Folder 2)
      - Student Inquiries, 1935-1962; 1 folder (Folder 3)
    - Publisher and Dealer Correspondence, 1919-1948; 2 boxes (1 partial)
      - General Publisher Correspondence, 1926-1939; 1 folder (Folder 4)
      - Publishers Bills and Orders, 1923-1946; 1 folder (Folder 5)
      - Publishers Bills and Orders, 1929-1945; 1 folder (Folder 6)
      - Publishers Bills and Orders, 1931-1948; 1 folder (Folder 1)
      - Publishers Bills and Orders, 1932-1939; 1 folder (Folder 2)
      - Publishers Bills and Orders, 1938-1946; 1 folder (Folder 3)
      - Elkin Mathews, 1919-1935; 1 folder (Folder 4)
      - General Dealer Correspondence, 1921-1936; 1 folder (Folder 5)
    - Printing Services, 1920-1941; more than 3 folders
      - Société Générale d'Imprimerie et d'Édition, 1922-1941; 1 folder (Folder 1)
      - Imprimerie Darantiere, 1920-1938; 1 folder (Folder 2)
      - Imprimerie Darantiere Samples, undated; 1 folder (Folder 3-5)
    - Review Services, 1934-1959; 1 folder (Folder 1)
    - Myrsine Moschos, undated; 1 folder (Folder 2)
    - Miscellaneous Business, 1919-1938; 1 folder (Folder 3)
    - Miscellaneous Brief Messages, undated; 1 folder (Folder 4)
  - Business Records, 1913-1958; more than 14 boxes (2 partial)
    - Inventories, Order Records, Clients, 1919-1949; 11 boxes (2 partial)
      Notebooks and loose-leaf records of sales, orders, customers, reviews, and subscriptions.
      Arranged chronologically by year.
      - Inventories, Order Records, Clients, 1919-1922; 1 box (Folder 5-6)
      - Inventories, Order Records, Clients, 1922-1923; 1 box (Folder 7)
      - Inventories, Order Records, Clients, 1922-1924; 1 box (Folder 1)
      - Inventories, Order Records, Clients, 1923-1929; 1 box (Folder 2)
      - Inventories, Order Records, Clients, 1923-1949; 1 box (Folder 3)
      - Inventories, Order Records, Clients, 1924; 1 box (Folder 4)
      - Inventories, Order Records, Clients, 1924; 1 box (Folder 1)
      - Inventories, Order Records, Clients, 1924-1925; 1 box (Folder 2)
      - Inventories, Order Records, Clients, 1925; 1 box (Folder 3-5)
      - Inventories, Order Records, Clients, 1926; 1 box (Folder 1-3)
      - Inventories, Order Records, Clients, 1926-1933; 1 box (Folder 4)
      - Inventories, Order Records, Clients, 1927; 1 box (Folder 5)
      - Inventories, Order Records, Clients, 1927; 1 box (Folder 1)
      - Inventories, Order Records, Clients, 1928; 1 box (Folder 2)
      - Inventories, Order Records, Clients, 1928-1933; 1 box (Folder 3)
      - Inventories, Order Records, Clients, 1929; 1 box (Folder 4)
      - Inventories, Order Records, Clients, 1930-1938; 1 box (Folder 5)
      - Inventories, Order Records, Clients, 1931; 1 box (Folder 1-2)
      - Inventories, Order Records, Clients, 1932; 1 box (Folder 3)
      - Inventories, Order Records, Clients, 1933; 1 box (Folder 4-7)
      - Inventories, Order Records, Clients, 1933; 1 box (Folder 1)
      - Inventories, Order Records, Clients, 1933-1940; 1 box (Folder 2)
      - Inventories, Order Records, Clients, 1934; 1 box (Folder 3-4)
      - Inventories, Order Records, Clients, 1935; 1 box (Folder 5-6)
      - Inventories, Order Records, Clients, 1935; 1 box (Folder 1)
      - Inventories, Order Records, Clients, 1935-1939; 1 box (Folder 2)
      - Inventories, Order Records, Clients, 1936; 1 box (Folder 3-5)
      - Inventories, Order Records, Clients, 1936-1937; 1 box (Folder 1)
      - Inventories, Order Records, Clients, 1936-1939; 1 box (Folder 2)
      - Inventories, Order Records, Clients, 1938-1939; 1 box (Folder 3)
      - Inventories, Order Records, Clients, 1939-1940; 1 box (Folder 4)
      - Inventories, Order Records, Clients, 1940; 1 box (Folder 1-2)
      - Inventories, Order Records, Clients, 1941; 1 box (Folder 3)
      - Inventories, Order Records, Clients, 1946-1947; 1 box (Folder 4)
      - Inventories, Order Records, Clients, undated; 1 box (Folder 5)
      - Inventories, Order Records, Clients, undated; 1 box (Folder 1-3)
    - Financial Records, 1913-1958; more than 3 boxes (1 partial)
      - Bills and Invoices, 1919-1921; 1 folder (Folder 4)
      - Bills and Invoices, 1921-1940; 1 folder (Folder 5)
      - Bills and Invoices, 1923-1924; 1 folder (Folder 6)
      - Bills and Invoices, 1924-1932; 1 folder (Folder 7)
      - Bills and Invoices, 1927-1958; 1 folder (Folder 8)
      - Bills and Invoices, 1928-1957; 1 folder (Folder 9)
      - Checks and Check Stubs, 1919-1939; 1 box
      - Checks and Check Stubs, 1919-1939; 1 box (Folder 1-3)
        Includes a check from Sylvia Beach to Ernest Hemingway.
      - Lloyds Bank Records, 1921-1948; 1 folder (Folder 4)
      - Insurance Documents, 1926-1940; 1 folder (Folder 5)
      - Tax Documents, 1913-1940; 1 folder (Folder 6)
      - Tax Documents, 1920-1941; 1 folder (Folder 7)
    - Rue Dupuytren, 1919-1922; 1 folder (Folder 1)
    - Rue de L'Odéon, 1924-1944; 1 folder (Folder 2)
  - Miscellaneous, 1912-1962; 5 boxes (2 partial)
    - Friends of Shakespeare & Company, 1934-1937; 1 folder (Folder 3-4)
    - Articles on Shakespeare & Company, 1924-1938; 4 folders
      - Publishers' Weekly Article on Shakespeare & Company on Page 1261, 1924; 1 folder (Folder 5)
      - The Bookman Article on Shakespeare and Company on Page 403, 1925; 1 folder (Folder 6)
      - Town & Country Article on Shakespeare & Company on Page 58, 1926; 1 folder (Folder 7)
      - The Delphian Quarterly Article on Shakespeare & Company on Page 34, 1938; 1 folder (Folder 8)
    - Sotheby's Sale of Joyce, Whitman, Blake Items, 1935; more than 5 folders
      - Sotheby's Sale Correspondence, 1935; 1 folder (Folder 1-2)
      - Sotheby's Sale Mailing List, 1935; 1 folder (Folder 3)
      - Sotheby's Sale Catalogue, 1935; 1 folder (Folder 4-9)
      - Sotheby's Sale Publicity: The New Yorker, 1935; 1 folder (Folder 10)
      - Sotheby's Sale Publicity: Time and Trade, 1935; 1 folder (Folder 11)
    - Joyce, Michael, 1930-1936; 3 folders
      - Frankfurter Zeitung Publication of Michael Joyce Work Attributed to James Joyce, 1931 August 11-October 2; 1 folder (Folder 1)
        Letters and related material.
      - Newspaper Clippings and Copy of The Blue Peter Magazine, 1930-1936; 1 folder (Folder 2)
        Sent to Sylvia Beach by James Joyce containing story by Michael Joyce.
      - Brody, Daniel to James Joyce Regarding Frankfurter Zeitung Incident, 1931 July 30; 1 folder (Folder 3)
    - Poster Advertising Works of James Joyce and Gertrude Stein, circa 1928; 1 folder
    - Miscellaneous Book Jackets, undated; 1 folder (Folder 4)
      Book jackets of books shelved at Shakespeare & Company.
    - Stationery and Signage, 1921-1959; portions of 2 boxes
      - Stationery, Calling Cards, Envelopes, Letterhead, 1921-1938; 1 folder (Folder 5-8)
        Includes membership cards, blank receipts, bookplates, autograph drafts of pamphlets, postcards, advertisements, overdue notices, order forms, and advertisements.
      - Bookshop Signs, undated; 1 folder (Folder 9)
      - Clippings and Miscellaneous, 1959; 1 folder (Folder 1)
      - Rubber Stamps, undated; 1 folder (Folder 2)
    - Business Reference Works, 1912-1962; more than 3 folders
      - Booksellers Announcements and Catalogues, 1912-1962; 1 folder (Folder 3-5)
      - American Book Prices Current, 1959-1960; 1 folder (Folder 6)
      - "Pitman's Commercial Copy & Exercise Book" No. 1-2, undated; 1 folder (Folder 7)
- Series 3: Writings and Translations, 1927-1969; 13 boxes (1 partial)
  Writings and Translations documents Sylvia Beach's works, including her memoir, Shakespeare & Company, and a number of articles and speeches. The series also contains information on Beach's translations of works by Henri Michaux and Adrienne Monnier.
  Arranged alphabetically by author, starting with Sylvia Beach's works followed by her translations. Minor articles and speeches are filed at the end of the series.
  - Shakespeare & Company, 1937-1962; 9 boxes (1 partial)
    - Drafts, undated; 4 folders (Folder 1-12)
    - Drafts, undated; 15 folders (Folder 1-14)
      Includes sections on Bridgeton, NJ and Paris, France.
    - Drafts, undated; 5 folders (Folder 1-5)
      Includes sections on Bridgeton, NJ and Paris, France; Serbia, Spain, and Palais Royale; and WWII Occupation.
    - Harcourt Brace, 1950-1962; 3 boxes (2 partial)
      - Harcourt Brace Correspondence, 1950-1959; 1 folder (Folder 6-8)
        Includes correspondence with editor Margaret Marshall
      - Harcourt Brace Correspondence, 1959-1962; 1 folder (Folder 1-2)
        Includes correspondence with editor Margaret Marshall.
      - Publicity, 1959-1961; 1 folder (Folder 3-4)
      - Catalogs and Samples, 1958-1962; 1 folder (Folder 5)
      - Harcourt Publishing Envelopes, 1959-1961; 1 folder (Folder 6)
      - Harcourt Party for Sylvia Beach, 1959 October; 1 folder (Folder 7)
        Includes invitations and guest list at Gotham Hotel.
      - Hardcover Edition, 1956; 1 folder 2 copies (Folder 8)
        Marked up with Sylvia Beach's corrections.
      - Paperback Edition, 1959; 1 folder 2 copies (Folder 1)
      - Reviews, 1959 August-1960 October; 1 folder (Folder 2-6)
      - Royalty Statements, 1959-1961; 1 folder (Folder 7)
      - Presentation Copies, 1959-1961; 1 folder (Folder 8)
    - Faber and Faber, London, 1959-1960; portions of 2 boxes
      - Proofs, undated; 1 folder (Folder 9)
      - Correspondence, 1959-1960; 1 folder (Folder 1)
      - Publicity, 1960; 1 folder (Folder 2)
    - Le Figaro Littéraire, 1959-1962; portions of 2 boxes
      - Correspondence, 1959-1962; 1 folder (Folder 3)
      - Odette Arnaud (Literary Agent), 1959-1960; 1 folder (Folder 4)
      - Translation, undated; 2 folders (Folder 5-6)
      - Illustrations, undated; 1 folder (Folder 7)
      - Publicity, 1960-1962; 1 folder (Folder 1)
      - Reviews, 1960; 1 folder (Folder 2)